Aqib Mehmood

SQA Engineer

I am a passionate and highly motivated ISTQB® Certified Software Quality Assurance and Security Tester with *three years* of dedicated experience in testing blockchain applications. I am excited to bring my passion for software quality and security testing to your team.

i.aqibmehmood@gmail.com

+92 341 7823422

Karachi, Pakistan

]:]

aqib-mehmood.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/aqib-mehmood422

WORK EXPERIENCE

SQA Engineer BlockApex Labs

06/2023 - 08/2024

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Performed various functional and non-functional testing including API testing, Performance testing, and Regression testing.
- Implemented and maintained e2e Web/API automation scripts for multiple projects using Selenium & Cypress.

SQA Engineer Xord

03/2022 - 06/2023

Responsibilities/Tasks

- Analysed application requirements through SRS and Figma design provided by the client.
- Designed test scenarios and test cases for functional and nonfunctional testing.
- Conducted API testing, Performance testing, Functional testing, Automated regression testing, and System testing by executing test cases.

Bug Bounty Hunter

HackerOne (Freelancing)

12/2020 - 03/2022

Achievements/Tasks

- I got rewards and bounties from more than ten companies for my contributions to various bug bounty programs like Facebook and Shopify.
- I received Hall of Fame for reporting valid security vulnerabilities from Inflectra, Picoworkers, and Sync.com Inc.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Bahria University Karachi Campus

09/2018 - 08/2022

3.43 CGPA out of 4

CERTIFICATION

ISTQB® Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) ♂

11/2022

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Automated QA Testing Manual QA Testing

API Testing Performance Testing

Blockchain Application Testing Dapp Testing

Smart Contract Unit Testing Security Testing

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Languages

Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, Bash

Web/UI Automation Tools

Selenium, Cypress

Testing Frameworks

TestNG, Chai, Mocha, Page Object Model (POM) Design pattern

API Automation Tools

Cypress, Postman

Performance Testing Tools

IMeter

Security Testing Tools

Burp Suite

Other Tools

Github, Jenkins, Jira, Trello

KEY PROJECTS

Elektrik DEX 🗹

- Elektrik is a decentralized exchange set to launch natively on the LightLink network, built on the foundation of Uniswap v3.
- I was responsible for conducting QA automated testing activities.

Infra DApp 🗹

- A blockchain-based solution enables businesses to reach authentic and relevant audiences whereas influencers promote businesses to match their passion.
- I have conducted different testing activities from functional testing to API testing, performance testing, and smart contract functional testing.

Sonar Wallet 🗹

- Sonar Wallet a multichain, DeFi wallet that manages and stores multiple accounts.
- I was responsible for conducting all the testing activities (functional, non-function, automated and security testing), and collaborating with the development team to resolve issues promptly.